foxcreekleather.com 2016-04-02

# Contact Us – Fox Creek Leather

If you have any questions or comments, please contact us. However, many questions are answered in our FAQ which you may want to consult before calling

E-mail: [customerservice@foxcreekleather.com](mailto:customerservice@foxcreekleather.com)  

Hours: 8:00am-6:00pm Monday-Friday and 10:00am-4:00pm Saturday EDT. We can sometimes be found in the office on Sundays and weekday evenings.

Telephone: (800) 766-4165 or +1 (276) 773-3131  

Fax: (276) 773-3127  

Address:  
Fox Creek Leather Company  
2029 Elk Creek Parkway  
Independence, VA 24348

Directions:  

####  Follow us on these popular social sites:

Back to the top

The Better Business Bureau only approves membership to businesses that have a proven track record. Although Fox Creek Leather has been around since 1983, we know it can be a leap of faith to order products online. We want you to be confident you can trust Fox Creek Leather to handle your purchase with courtesy and respect. 

Back to the top

#### Requirements:

  * 25% down payment at time of order.
  * You have 8 weeks to pay the balance.

If after 8 weeks the amount has not been paid in full, the order will be canceled and the amount paid will be refunded minus a $25 restocking fee. 

You have the right to pay your layaway in full anytime before the due date. You may cancel your layaway at anytime during the 8 week period. Your order will be canceled and the amount paid will be refunded minus a $25 restocking fee. 

Your price is set at time of order. The price will not be adjusted for sales or price increases. 

Please purchase the item you wish to place on layaway. There is a section for notes at check out. Please place a note there stating you want to place this item or items on layaway. Your credit card will only be charged 25% of your order. 

Items that are on the Blowout Sale are not eligible for the layaway program. 

For further questions, please contact us. 

Back to the top

  1. Chaps & Pants
    1. How should my chaps fit?
    2. What does braided or not braided mean?
    3. What about the hem on my chaps or pants?
    4. Why do I need to give my measurements for chaps? Can't I just say I need a large?
    5. Are the chaps lined?
    6. Which are better, overpants or chaps?
    7. Why do I need to measure to the floor?
    8. Are braided chaps for women only?
    9. How do I put on my chaps?
  2. Jackets
    1. Does the liner go down the sleeves?
    2. Do your jackets have armor?
    3. How do I know I have the best fit possible?
  3. Sizing
    1. How much longer is a long?
    2. Why do I have to measure to the floor?
    3. Is your sizing standard to other companies?
    4. How are your items supposed to fit?
  4. About Leather
    1. What does naked leather mean?
    2. What does drum dyed mean?
    3. What are the benefits of heavy leather?
    4. When do I need to treat my leathers and how often?
    5. What are range marks?
  5. Custom Orders
    1. How long does it take to make a custom order?
    2. Will you customize an item I have now?
    3. How much can I customize an item?
    4. Why do you have to send me a try on jacket? Can't you make it from the measurements that I give you?
    5. How much does it cost?
    6. Who do you recommend for custom work that you can't do?
  6. Returns & Exchanges
    1. Do I have to pay return shipping?
    2. Do I need a return authorization number?
    3. What if I refuse my package?
  7. Warranty & Repairs
    1. Who pays for shipping on Warranty/Repair work?
    2. Do all repairs need to be done at Fox Creek Leather?
    3. Can I replace my item with a different style or size under the lifetime guarantee?
    4. I need to wear my gear soon. Can you send me a replacement or loaner right away?
    5. My product is discontinued. What happens if it needs to be replaced under the lifetime guarantee?
    6. Fox Creek is installing my patches on a replacement vest/jacket. What happens if I am not happy with them?
    7. How soon will my gear be repaired and returned to me?
  8. Miscellaneous
    1. Do you have an affiliate program?
    2. Do you have a catalog you can send me?
    3. Do you have a layaway program?
    4. Do you offer military discounts?
    5. How do I pay with PayPal?
    6. Can I change my shipping address on a package that's in transit?
    7. Are the Easy Brackets covered under warranty?
  9. Do you have a store?
    1. What are your hours and location?
    2. Are there hotels or camping nearby?
    3. How far away from me are you?
    4. Do you have your jackets, chaps, vests and other products there for me to try on?
    5. Will there be someone there to measure and help me?

  1. Chaps & Pants 
    1. How should my chaps fit? 

You should be able to comfortably tighten the belt, without having to put it on the first or last hole, or by letting out the lacing in the back no more than a few inches. At your thighs your chaps should be snug, but not to the degree that they cause discomfort. Wearing your riding boots, your chaps should nick the floor on the inside of your boot. Remember that your chaps will conform to your body over time; a fit that is a bit snug initially is preferable to one that is too loose.

    2. What does braided and not braided mean? 

Our braided chaps have a thin line of braided piping that goes around the waist (yoke) of the chaps. Our plain (unbraided) chaps do not have the braided piping.

    3. What about the hem on my chaps or pants? 

Leather does not need to be hemmed as it will not fray like fabric does.

    4. Why do I need to give my measurements for chaps? Can't I just say I need a large? 

To ensure that you get the best possible fit on the first try. We have found that people who do not give measurements and guess at their size are often unsatisfied with the fit of their chaps.

    5. Are the chaps lined? 

Yes, our Men's and Women's Lined Motorcycle Chaps and Deluxe Lined Leather Chaps have a quilted lining that runs from the belt down to the first snap on the legs. Our standard motorcycle chaps come unlined. 

    6. Which are better, overpants or chaps? 

Overpants offer greater protection in a crash and from wind and water. However, chaps are lighter and easier to wear. Many people find that they get all the protection that they want with chaps while others want to be a little warmer.

    7. Why do I need to measure to the floor? 

See: Sizing: Why do I need to measure to the floor?

    8. Are braided chaps for women only? 

No, they are for men and women.

    9. How do I put on my chaps? 

We recommend reading this article from our blog: [A must read for any new chaps wearer](http://foxcreekleather.wordpress.com/2006/01/18/recommended-process-to-put-on-chaps-for-first-timers/).

  2. Jackets 
    1. Does the liner go down the sleeves? 

If a jacket is described as having a "full sleeve" liner, it does in fact extend down the sleeves. All of our jackets have a nylon shell lining the interior of the sleeve regardless of liner type.

    2. Do your jackets have armor? 

Most of our men's jackets have provisional pockets that give you the option of using armor. We sell Forcefield elbow, shoulder and back armor inserts.

    3. How do I know I have the best fit possible? 

We recommend reading this article from our blog: [How Your Motorcycle Jacket Is Supposed To Fit](http://foxcreekleather.wordpress.com/2012/01/04/how-your-motorcycle-jacket-is-supposed-to-fit/).

  3. Sizing 
    1. How much longer is a long? 

For jackets it is 2" longer in the sleeves and the body. For vests, it is 2" longer in length. For chaps, it is 2" longer.

    2. Why do I need to measure to the floor? 

When you sit your chaps/pants ride up. It's important to make sure that your chaps are long enough when sitting down that wind doesn't blow up your leg. If they are too short you can not do anything to lengthen them, but if they are too long you can alter them by cutting them to the length that you want. Only alter the length once you are sure that they fit you everywhere else. Please note that once your chaps/pants have been altered, they may not be returned for exchange or refund.

    3. Is your sizing standard to other companies'? 

No, most companies size their garments differently. That is why we often ask for measurements. 

    4. How are your items supposed to fit? 

The main thing to remember is your comfort. We recommend reading these articles from our blog: [How Your Motorcycle Jacket Is Supposed To Fit](http://foxcreekleather.wordpress.com/2012/01/04/how-your-motorcycle-jacket-is-supposed-to-fit/) and [How Your Leather Vest Is Supposed To Fit](http://foxcreekleather.wordpress.com/2012/03/23/how-your-leather-vest-is-supposed-to-fit/). You can contact us with any questions you have as well.

  4. About Leather 
    1. What does naked leather mean? 

The grain of the hide is unaltered and has only been dyed. Only the highest quality hides can be used to make naked leather. Lesser hides are corrected by sanding to remove imperfections. More Information »

    2. What does drum dyed mean? 

It means the leather was immersed in a drum of dye and tumbled. This method provided the most even and permanent dying that will not bleed. More Information »

    3. What are the benefits of heavy leather? 

Heavy leather provides more protection. Our men's jackets and chaps are typically 1.4-1.6 mm thick.

    4. When do I need to treat my leathers and how often? 

It depends on your exposure to the elements how often you need to treat your leather. All of our leather comes treated from the factory and does not need to be treated right away. We do recommend that you treat your leather at least every 6 months. Always be sure to clean and dry before treating. Read our Leather Care Guide for more detailed information.

    5. What are range marks? 

Leather is a natural material and as such it is subject to minor blemishes and imperfections. These are referred to as range marks. They are actually healed scars and scratches that the animal incurred while alive. These are not defects but authenticate that the material is real leather and make each piece truly one of a kind.

  5. Custom Orders 
    1. How long does it take to make a custom order? 

It depends on the item and the time of year. It will also depend on how many items are in front of yours. It may take up to 8-10 weeks.

    2. Will you customize an item I have now? 

No. We only make special orders from scratch.

    3. How much can I customize an item? 

We are limited as to what we can do. Click here for more info. 

    4. Why do you have to send me a try on jacket? Can't you make it from the measurements that I give you? 

Because over time we have found that this is the best method for ensuring that you get the proper fit.

    5. How much does it cost? 

The price varies and depends on what you want done. It will always be based on the regular price of the item as sale prices do not apply to custom orders. Please see our Custom Order page for more information.

    6. Who do you recommend for custom work that you can't do? 

Nanci at Ace High Leathers in California does a wonderful job and has done a lot of great custom leather goods for our customers in the past. Her phone number is 530-905-0505.

  6. Returns & Exchanges 
    1. Do I have to pay return shipping? 

Yes, you will be responsible for return shipping.

    2. Do I need a return authorization number? 

No. Just fill out the returns & exchanges form found on our website. 

    3. What if I refuse my package? 

Refused packages will incur the appropriate service charge.

  7. Warranty & Repairs

Please be sure to include the best phone number to reach you and the name the item was ordered under when returning any product for warranty/repair work. Products may be either Repaired or Replaced at our sole discretion.

    1. Who pays for shipping on Warranty/Repair work? 

The customer is responsible for returning the item to Fox Creek Leather. The repair/replacement will be returned to the customer at Fox Creek Leather's expense via standard ground shipping. Expedited shipping is available at the customer's expense. Please ask for a quote.

    2. Do all repairs need to be done at Fox Creek Leather? 

Some repairs can be done at local leather or shoe shops. If you need a simple repair done locally, please submit a quote to us at [customerservice@foxcreekleather.com](mailto:customerservice@foxcreekleather.com?subject=Local%20repair). We will contact you within 1 business day to let you know how much of the charge we will reimburse.

    3. Can I replace my item with a different style or size under the lifetime guarantee? 

No. If we determine the item should be replaced, we will send you an identical size and style. 

    4. I need my gear this weekend. Can you send me a replacement or loaner today? 

We cannot send replacements until we receive an item to evaluate whether it should be repaired or replaced, and we do not loan gear. Some repairs take longer than others - allow 3-4 weeks plus shipping time to receive your repaired gear. If you know you will be needing the repaired item on a specific date, please call (1-276-773-3131 or 800-766-4165) before sending it to us. 

    5. My product is discontinued. What happens if it needs to be replaced under the lifetime guarantee? 

If your product style has been discontinued and is determined to need replacement under the lifetime guarantee, we will give you a store credit for the original purchase price. This store credit may be used on any future purchase(s) at Fox Creek Leather.

    6. Who is responsible for reinstalling patches on my replaced/repaired item? 

Fox Creek Leather's Lifetime Guarantee ONLY covers the leather apparel purchased at Fox Creek Leather. Any patches/pins or other adornment added by the customer is not covered under the warranty. Fox Creek Leather sometimes installs patches at customer's request and expense, but that is not our primary sewing function. While we do everything in our power to follow your explicit instructions, we do NOT guarantee the results.

    7. How soon will my gear be repaired and returned to me? 

Once we receive your item in our Independence, Virginia facility, it will be placed in the production line. While repairs are important to us, they do not take precedence over current orders. If you need a rush put on your item, please call 1-276-773-3131 or 800-766-4165. We will evaluate if a RUSH can be placed on your repair and a RUSH fee of $50-150 must be paid before the work is accelerated. The fee is determined by the complexity of the repair. 

  8. Miscellaneous 
    1. Do you have an affiliate program? 

Yes, please [click here](http://affiliate.foxcreekleather.com/) for information about our program.

    2. Do you have a catalog you can send me? 

No, our Web site is our catalog. If you want to see a larger image or have any questions about our products, please contact us.

    3. Do you have a layaway program? 

We do have a layaway program. For more information, click here.

    4. Do you offer military discounts? 

Not only do we offer free shipping to military addresses, we offer a discount on regularly priced items for members of our military. We offer $25 off the regular price of a jacket and $10 off the regular price of a vest or chaps. Only one discount/promotion per order. 

    5. How do I pay with PayPal? 

You will be redirected to login to your PayPal account to verify the payment before submitting your order. When you submit your order, we will receive a payment confirmation automatically and all stock items should ship within 1-2 business days.

Please note that PayPal Express Checkout is not available if your order total is $0.

    6. Can I change my shipping address on a package that's in transit? 

If the package was shipped via USPS then we have no way of changing the shipping address once the package is shipped. However, we can change the address while the package is still in transit with UPS. If we have to call UPS the charge is $14. If we're able to complete the request online the charge is only $11.

    7. Are the Easy Brackets covered under warranty? 

[Click here](http://www.greatbikegear.com/index.php/limited-warranty/) to read the manufacture warranty.

  9. Come visit us at our store! 
    1. What are your hours and location? 

Our store is located at 2029 Elk Creek Parkway in Independence, VA. Our hours are Monday-Friday 8:00am-6:00pm, Saturday 10:00pm-4:00pm EST. For more information, please contact us.

    2. Are there hotels or camping nearby? 

Yes, right here in Independence is Grayson Inn & Suites (877-467-7144) and there are also several hotels about 15 miles away in Galax, VA, close to the Blue Ridge Parkway, and about 30 miles away in Wytheville, VA. Just 10 miles to the south of us is Sparta, NC, also close to the Blue Ridge Parkway, where you can also find hotels.

We are in a rural area with several State & National Parks nearby. Just 6 miles from us is Fulton Road Bed & Breakfast. Their number is 276-773-2627 and email fultonroadinn@embarqmail.com. There is a biker rest stop called Bear Claw Holler that is 39 miles away. You can call 276-388-3461 or email bearclawholler@yahoo.com.

    3. How far away from me are you? 

You can use the Google Maps tool on our Help page to quickly get directions.

    4. Do you have your jackets, chaps, vests and other products there for me to try on? 

We do have a huge inventory of items here. We try to keep stock in the things that we offer online. Occasionally we do sell out of a product or if it's something that we normally dropship we may not have it here. You can call us to verify before coming. 

    5. Will there be someone there to measure and help me? 

Yes, we always have knowledgeable staff on hand ready and willing to help you in any way we can.

Back to the top

Need help finding a product, article or review on our site? Use our search option above to find what you need. If you still need help, please contact us. 

Back to the top

Custom orders incur an alteration fee. This is added to the regular price of the item because sale prices are not valid on custom orders. [Contact us](http://www.foxcreekleather.com/help/) if you have questions regarding alteration fees for a special or custom order.

Special orders on jackets, vests, and chaps may take up to 8-10 weeks. We realize this is a long time, but such a high quality garment with a lifetime guarantee is well worth the wait. 

We will try to fit any body. However, we are limited as to what we can alter or change about a pattern. With the exception of chaps, all orders will be made from scratch as an item cannot be altered. Below is a list of what we can do to customize your leather garment. 

#### Jackets and Chaps

  * We can add or remove length from the sleeves and/or body. However, we will not remove length from the sleeve and add length to the body or vice versa. It has to be done in 1" increments with a maximum of 4". Cost - $125.
  * We can make an item without certain features (such as epaulets, reflective piping, the perforated piece on the Bomber, removable liner, etc.). Cost - $0.
  * We cannot alter the collar type/size and we cannot alter the shoulder width.
  * We cannot make backwards or odd sized chaps (such as XL waist, S thigh) but we can alter the pair that fits your thigh to fit you in the waist. Cost - $40.
  * Extra long or larger chaps may be made with additional panels to keep the cost/time down.
  * We have the ability to make larger sizes than what we stock but we are limited. The price would depend on what you need. We would send you the closest thing in stock to try before we would special order it for you.

#### Vests

  * We can add or remove length from the body in 1" increments with a maximum of 4". The length must be adjusted the same in the front as in the back. Cost - $60.
  * We can make a vest with the gun pocket on the right hand side for left handed persons or with two standard pockets instead of a gun pocket. Cost - $60.
  * We can make a vest with a different type of snap. Cost - depends on snap chosen.
  * We have the ability to make larger sizes than what we stock but we are limited. The price would depend on what you need. We would send you the closest thing in stock to try before we would special order it for you.

Special orders cannot be returned for exchange or refund. We may require a non-refundable 50% deposit before making the order. 

We require a trial for size fitting process to ensure the fit. We would get your measurements and recommend a stock sized item for you to try. You would pay for the stock item and then return it. We must have the trial item back before proceeding with the special order. When the special order is ready we would then charge the alteration fees and ship the item out to you. 

We cannot customize or alter any sale/closeout items. 

Back to the top

Our lifetime guarantee covers the workmanship and materials on all of our American made chaps, jackets, vests and pants as long as they are owned by the original purchaser. This includes any problem with snaps, zippers, seams and grommets that arise due to normal use of the garment. If you have any problem, please [e-mail us](mailto:customerservice@foxcreekleather.com) or call (800) 766-4165. Upon approval of quote, we will arrange to have your garment repaired locally or the customer may send the item back to us.

Our guarantee does not cover the liner or any hardware attached to the liner. Our lifetime guarantee does not cover any reflective piping. Any garments that have been abused (accidents, knife fights, failure to properly maintain the garment) will not be covered. Gloves, saddlebags, windshield bags, toolbags, travelbags, boots and items in our accessories section are not covered.

Please note, items sent back within our 30 day return policy that have had pins or patches installed can be repaired but not replaced. Items sent back outside of the 30 day return policy will be repaired and not replaced. Items which cannot be repaired will be replaced with an item of the same size and style. No refunds.

Back to the top

### The return policy for Christmas orders will be extended until the last day of January.

#### Download and fill out this [Returns and Exchange Form](http://www.foxcreekleather.com/forms/returns_policy_20141111.pdf) to return your Fox Creek Leather products. 

Returns and exchanges should be made within 30 days of receipt of the item(s). If the item ordered does not fit properly, or if you are dissatisfied for any reason, contact us immediately so we may remedy the problem. We do not accept the return of used merchandise. 

There is no restocking fee for stock items returned in new condition within 30 days. All stock orders returned in less than new condition and/or after 30 days will be subject to a 20% restocking fee. 

If you are returning an item you bought on sale for a special order you will be charged the difference between the sale price and regular price plus any applicable alteration fees.

_Due to rising shipping costs, Fox Creek Leather has chosen to pay shipping on the initial shipment only. This is to keep from raising prices._

Fox Creek Leather will pay ground shipping for the initial order shipped to the customer (USA addresses only). Customer must pay return shipping on all items sent to us. Customers will be charged standard shipping fees on all exchanges sent. This fee will vary depending on what item is exchanged. Exchange shipping for small items is $5, $10 on chaps and vests, and $15 on jackets. Please note, expedited shipping is available at additional cost.

Fox Creek Leather does not accept refused packages. Packages that are returned to us as refused will incur a service charge.

We do not accept custom made items for exchange or refund.

There will be no refund or exchange on any damaged or abused item. Do not put pins, patches or embroidery on your garment until you are sure you want to keep the item. We will not accept any items that have been altered from their original form. For example, we will not accept chaps that have had the length trimmed.

Returns will not be accepted on socks or thermal under clothing.

If you receive gloves that are too small, _DO NOT_ force the fit. Please return them for the proper size. Gloves with split seams due to improper fit will not be exchanged or refunded. 

**If you receive boots that you need to return, the original box and all tags must be returned with the boots. All boots need to be returned to the address below, even if they were shipped from a different address.**

Please use the box you received or one of equal size; this will ensure that there will be no damage to the merchandise. Merchandise that is damaged due to improper return packaging may be refused/returned to the customer or incur a restocking fee. 

**Note:** Our returns & exchanges form requires [Adobe Reader](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep2.html), a free program. If you do not have Adobe Reader or wish to upgrade to a newer version, you may do so by following the below link.  

Please address all returns to:  
**Fox Creek Leather  
Returns & Exchanges  
2029 Elk Creek Parkway  
Independence, VA 24348**

If you have any questions regarding your return or exchange, please contact us at info (at) foxcreekleather.com or (800) 766-4165.

Back to the top

_Due to rising shipping costs, Fox Creek Leather has chosen to pay shipping on the initial U.S. shipment only. The customer is responsible for any subsequent shipping when exchanging their order. This is to keep from raising prices._

We offer free standard shipping (before tax) within the United States (including Hawaii, Alaska, and Puerto Rico). At our discretion, we may ship your package via USPS First Class, USPS Priority Mail, UPS Surepost, or UPS Ground. If you provide a PO Box, please also provide a street address.

Using the available free options, shipping times all vary between 1-7 business days depending on your location. Please see the UPS shipping map below. When free standard shipping is selected, we will ship by the least expensive method. UPS Surepost may delay delivery up to 3 days from the below UPS chart. Expedited shipping is available for an additional cost. Depending on the weight and destination, USPS Priority may not always be a free option.

Orders to APO or FPO addresses are shipped free of charge via USPS First Class or Priority Mail. 

All international shipping fees are the responsibility of the customer. We ship internationally via USPS or UPS. Please note, Fox Creek Leather is not responsible for any brokerage, duties, clearance fees, added value taxes, and/or other fees incurred due to your location or chosen shipping method. If you are shipping wildlife products including deerskin, buffalo, and elkskin for delivery outside the USA there will be a $15 handling charge and a delay of shipping by about 1 business week. This is because those items have to be inspected by the US Dept of Wildlife. **Please note for international customers only:** Do not return your order to us via UPS. Please use your local courier. Fox Creek Leather does not pay import fees. 

If your order is placed before 9:30am Eastern Time we will ship all in-stock items that day. Orders placed after 9:30am will be shipped the following day.

The following is an example of how domestic expedited shipping works. On Friday at 8:30am (EST), you place your order and request 3-day shipping. Your purchase will ship that day and arrive the afternoon of next Wednesday. If you had waited until Friday afternoon and chosen 3-day shipping your order would have arrived next Thursday afternoon.

UPS does not pick up on Saturday. Expedited shipments placed Friday after 9:30am (EST) will not be shipped until Monday.

Back to the top

Effective January 18, 2013

#### Overview

Fox Creek Leather will not spam you. Your personal information will not be used for any purpose other than to process your order. If requested we will add your e-mail address to our newsletter mailing list. We will never share, sell, or rent our mailing list. Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. Fox Creek Leather knows how vital your personal information is and how important that you know all ways your information is used and shared. This notice describes our privacy policy. We share customer information only as described below. By visiting www.foxcreekleather.com, you accept the terms of this notice.

#### What information does Fox Creek Leather collect?

The information we learn from visitors to foxcreekleather.com helps determine the types of products we offer and helps us improve our products and website. The types of information we gather:

#### Personal Information

When you place an order with us we will ask you for your name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address. You may choose to provide your credit card information to make a payment or you may send us a money-order, bank wire transfer, or pay via paypal instead. Your information will only be used to process your order and such purposes as responding to your requests and communicating with you.

#### Automatic Information:

Some information we collect and analyze includes the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, and platform; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our Web site, including date and time; cookie number; products you viewed or searched for; and the phone number you used to call our 800 number. We may also use browser data such as cookies, Flash cookies (also known as Flash Local Shared Objects), or similar data on certain parts of our Web site for fraud prevention and other purposes. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

#### Mobile: 

When you access www.foxcreekleather.com, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. Most mobile devices provide users with the ability to disable location services. Most likely, these controls are located in the device's settings menu. If you have questions about how to disable your device's location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer.

#### E-mail:

We often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from foxcreekleather.com if your computer supports such capabilities. When you contact us through foxcreekleather.com or email us, you are communicating with us electronically. Should you contact us by email, we may reply to you by email or by telephone. You have the option to sign up for our e-newsletter which offers an unsubscribe link in every issue. You will never receive unsolicited “spam” emails. You agree that all agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications that we provide to you electronically satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing.

#### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your e-mail address added to our newsletter mailing list. When placing an order or recommending a product you can choose to uncheck the box requesting that your e-mail address be added to our mailing list. If you are a newsletter subscriber and no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or by emailing us at customerservice (at) foxcreekleather.com.

You will be notified if your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

#### Children’s Use of Website

Fox Creek Leather does not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use foxcreekleather.com only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

#### Shipping and Credit Card Processing

We employ outside companies to deliver packages, provide marketing assistance, provide search results and links (including paid listings and links), and process credit card payments. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

#### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

#### Terms of Use, Notices, and Revisions

If you choose to visit foxcreekleather.com, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, resolution of disputes, and application of the law of the commonwealth of Virginia. If you have any concern about privacy at foxcreekleather.com, please contact us with a thorough description, and we will try to resolve it. Our business changes constantly, and our Privacy Notice and the Terms of Use below will change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, but you should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers.

#### Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If you're personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update it by emailing customer service at customerservice (at) foxcreekleather.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. Typically you can expect an email or telephone reply within one business day.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use persistent cookies to enable shopping cart, to track Web site use, and for remarketing purposes. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. You may find more information about cookies at <http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/>.

The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the Web site of its manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of foxcreekleather.com's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or make an online purchase.

#### Clear Gifs

Our third party advertising partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. All information entered throughout the checkout process is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Our SSL certificate is issued by [Comodo](http://www.comodo.com/). At no point in time do we transfer your information over a non encrypted connection.

Additional measures we take to secure your information include protecting our server by placing it behind a hardware firewall, partnering with [ScanAlert](http://www.scanalert.com/) to proactively monitor our Web site for security flaws, and a daily audit of our server for intrusion.

However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at customerservice (at) foxcreekleather.com. Typically you can expect an email or telephone reply within one business day.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact customer service at Fox Creek Leather by e-mail at customerservice (at) foxcreekleather.com or by phone at 1-800-766-4165. 

#### Business Transitions

In the event Fox Creek Leather goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

#### Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

customerservice (at) foxcreekleather.com

or

Privacy Policy  
Fox Creek Leather  
2029 Elk Creek Parkway  
Independence VA, 24348 

Back to the top

The easiest, most economical way to clean leather is with a damp rag. If your leathers are really filthy, a soft bristle brush and a little water will take care of almost any amount of crud that you could manage to embed on your jacket. I like to use a damp rag and have an old tooth brush handy to clean out seams, creases, and zippers. If you are working on something that looks like hell struck with a bat, you can use saddle soap or Montana Pitch Blend Leather Oil Soap. Air dry your leather at room temperature* and apply a good conditioner. For all leather outerwear that will be exposed to the elements, I am partial to Montana Pitch Blend Leather Dressing. It is a blend of pine pitch, mink oil, and beeswax. It will soften up the most neglected leather and it is water repellent. I resurrected an old brittle bomber jacket that was rotting in my closet and had mold on it. I used a variety of leather care products on different parts of the jacket and the Leather Dressing was the hands down winner. 

All light colored rags blacken when the cleaning and conditioning products are rubbed into our black leather. No reason to panic. All of our leather is drum dyed. There is plenty of dye to go around. Follow the directions when using the Montana Pitch Blend Leather Oil Soap. If you put it on a rag and rub it in full strength your rag will darken considerably. You are not gaining anything by using it full strength. Follow the directions and use it with water. 

Proper care is important to the longevity of your motorcycle leathers. Neglected leathers can dry and rot while well cared for leathers will increase in beauty as they age. At Fox Creek we use semi-aniline leather, which readily absorbs conditioning oils because there is a very little finish on its surface. A well conditioned set of leathers will attain a beautiful luster that shows off the natural full grain of the leather. The basic idea behind leather conditioning is to replace the natural oils that the leather loses during daily wear. These oils lubricate the leather, keeping it supple, and repel water and dirt which can break down the integrity of your leathers. 

_*High heat from a source like a wood stove will shrink wet or damp leather. It will not shrink the leather in a uniform manner. It shrinks the leather in spots and ruins it completely. I would also advise against drying your leather in intense hot sunlight. Well conditioned leather is less susceptible to heat damage._

The Original Doc Bailey's Leather Black actually contains a dye pigment that restores lost color. It also cleans, nourishes, and waterproofs. Doc Bailey's Leather Black gently cleans leather with specially formulated detergents which actually lift dirt out, opening the pores of the leather allowing the lanolin oil to flow into the leather nourishing and softening it. Doc Bailey's Leather Black actually penetrates deep into the leather to restores lost color. As a finishing touch, special waxes lock the color in which protects and waterproofs your leather.

Apply a small amount of Doc Bailey's Leather Black to a clean, dry sponge and wipe even over the surface to be treated. Rinse sponge after use. Allow to cure for 12 hours before exposing to moisture. Buff for higher shine if desired. Do not use on Buckskin or Suede. Product will darken all leather, always test in a discrete area. Reapply every 6 months or as needed. 

### **Caring for Elkskin Leather**

Light colored Elkskin will darken considerably when you apply conditioners and oils. Elkskin also tends to be more absorbent than other leathers so be conservative when applying oil. Elkskin can take a lot of abuse and be restored to it's original condition. Elkskin can also be washed. Melinda, our office manager, asked JR, one of our stitchers, to make her an elkskin purse. Somehow candy caramel melted inside the purse and it stuck together. Melinda threw it in a washing machine, dried it on high heat and it came out good as new. I am not endorsing this procedure. I'd recommend hand washing with a mild soap and drying it at room temperature. Elkskin is as tough as it is beautiful.

Paul & the Fox Creek Leather Staff
